♫I cherish every encounter with them♫
أعتز بكل لقاء معهم
♫Having fun and hugging in the rain♫
يلهون ويعانقون في المطر ♫
♫The troubles of youth belong to all mankind♫
مشاكل الشباب ملك البشرية جمعاء
♫We silently celebrate our youth♫
♫ نحتفل بصمت بشبابنا
♫I collect every parting with them♫
أجمع كل فراق معهم
♫Turning around in the wind and the taste of tears♫
تستدير في الريح وتذوق الدموع
♫The troubles of youth are left to everyone♫
مشاكل الشباب متروكة للجميع
♫I secretly miss our youth♫
♫ افتقد شبابنا سرًا
♫Hello, youth♫
♫ مرحبا شباب
♫Warm eyes♫
♫ عيون دافئة ♫
♫Looking at the farthest place♫
النظر إلى أبعد مكان ♫
♫We set out♫
انطلقنا ♫
♫To find the dream♫
لتجد الحلم ♫
♫It's good to be young♫
♫ من الجيد أن تكون شابًا
♫The hot waves♫
♫ الموجات الحارة ♫
♫Have the warmest power♫
♫ تمتع بأقصى قوة ♫
♫Guarding the light of youth♫
حراسة نور الشباب
This is too cramped to sleep.
هذا ضيق جدا للنوم.
I'm not taking up your place.
أنا لا أشغل مكانك.
You're not, but they are.
أنت لست كذلك ، لكنهم كذلك.
Your window didn't break.
نافذتك لم تنكسر.
Why did you come here?
لماذا أتيت هنا؟
It didn't break.
لم ينكسر.
There was just a crack on it.
كان هناك صدع فيه.
But it broke after my dad tried to repair it.
لكنها تعطلت بعد أن حاول والدي إصلاحها.
Kuan, You've placed it right
كوان ، لقد وضعتها بشكل صحيح
It mustn't be upside down.
لا يجب أن يكون رأسًا على عقب.
He can't turn it upside down.
لا يمكنه قلبها رأساً على عقب.
Why don't we just let him do this?
لماذا لا نسمح له فقط بفعل هذا؟
Can you do this? Qiang.
هل بإمكانك فعل هذا؟  تشيانغ.
Give me the plate.
أعطني الطبق.
Of course.
بالتاكيد.
I'll get them something to eat later.
سأحضر لهم شيئًا ليأكلوه لاحقًا.
You don't have to.
لا داعي لذلك.
Too many people are there.
هناك الكثير من الناس.
Don't go back tonight.
لا تعود الليلة.
Just stay here
فقط ابقى هنا
and help us.
وساعدنا.
I can help Mr. Tan with the window.
يمكنني مساعدة السيد تان في النافذة.
You know he's a...
أنت تعلم أنه ...
He's...
إنه ...
Got it.
فهمتك.
I understand.
أفهم.
Are you clear?
هل انت واضح
[Episode 6]
[الحلقة 6]
Just in case,
فقط في حالة،
I want to reconfirm.
أريد أن أعيد التأكيد.
Have you finished your homework?
هل انتهيت من واجبك المنزلي؟
We don't have homework today, right?
ليس لدينا واجب منزلي اليوم ، أليس كذلك؟
No.
لا.
I guess we don't have homework today.
أعتقد أنه ليس لدينا واجب منزلي اليوم.
I believe Mr. Yang told us
أعتقد أن السيد يانغ قال لنا
to be careful when setting off fireworks.
توخي الحذر عند بدء الألعاب النارية.
What else?
ماذا بعد؟
Is that all you've remembered?
هل هذا كل ما تذكرته؟
Is there any homework to do?
هل هناك أي واجبات منزلية يجب القيام بها؟
I guess there's not.
أعتقد أنه لا يوجد.
Oh my.
يا بلادي.
I'm not sleepy anymore.
لم أعد أشعر بالنعاس.
Let's listen to the radio.
دعنا نستمع إلى الراديو.
Don't step on me.
لا تخطو علي.
Stop, and listen to this channel.
توقف واستمع إلى هذه القناة.
Miss Cloud.
ملكة جمال كلاود.
Don't step on me again.
لا تخطو علي مرة أخرى.
After four hours...
بعد أربع ساعات ...
I like Miss Cloud, too.
أنا أحب Miss Cloud أيضًا.
A girl with a sweet voice
فتاة ذات صوت حلو
must be a beauty.
يجب أن يكون جمال.
Definitely.
بالتااكيد.
How can the voice
كيف يمكن للصوت
have anything to do with the appearance?
هل لها علاقة بالمظهر؟
Anyway,
على أي حال،
she can't be prettier than the belle of Xiaoji Street.
لا يمكن أن تكون أجمل من حسناء شارع شياوجي.
How boring you are.
كم أنت ممل.
...who is listening to the radio.
... من يستمع إلى الراديو.
♫You have a very soft heart♫
لديك قلب رقيق جدا ♫
♫So soft♫
♫ ناعم جدا ♫
♫Alone in tears in the morning♫
وحيد في البكاء في الصباح
♫Your love is so real♫
حبك حقيقي جدا ♫
♫I know you♫
♫ أعرفك ♫
Sleep.
نايم.
It has been a week.
لقد كان أسبوع.
So is the transfer student coming or not?
إذن هل الطالب المنتقل قادم أم لا؟
He skipped classes
لقد تخطى الصفوف
without telling his parents.
دون إخبار والديه.
He has been absent for a week.
لقد كان غائبا لمدة أسبوع.
What an unruly guy.
يا له من رجل جامح.
You know,
أنت تعرف،
when I was marking homework,
عندما كنت أحدد واجباتي المدرسية ،
Mr. Yang was talking to his parents on the phone.
كان السيد يانغ يتحدث إلى والديه على الهاتف.
No ordinary senior three students
لا يوجد ثلاثة طلاب كبار عاديين
dare to change schools.
يجرؤ على تغيير المدارس.
I heard his family
سمعت عائلته
owns a chicken restaurant.
يمتلك مطعم دجاج.
He must be rich.
يجب أن يكون غنيا.
I heard that, too.
سمعت ذلك ايضا
He was expelled from
تم طرده من
from his old school
من مدرسته القديمة
before he studies at our school.
قبل أن يدرس في مدرستنا.
He must be a really tough guy.
يجب أن يكون رجلا قويا حقا.
It looks that
يبدو أن
there will be a storm right away.
ستكون هناك عاصفة على الفور.
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
Why are you wearing glasses?
لماذا ترتدي نظارة؟
Sorry, I'm putting it away.
آسف ، أنا أضعه بعيدًا.
Take my backpack.
خذ حقيبتي.
Hurry up.
عجلوا.
Who's the boss here?
من هو الرئيس هنا؟
I...I'm a repeat student,
أنا ... أنا طالب مكرر ،
21 years old.
العمر 21 سنة.
I'm the eldest.
أنا الأكبر.
Sit...sit down.
اجلس ... اجلس.
I'm asking who's in charge here.
أنا أسأل من المسؤول هنا.
Me.
أنا.
I'm on duty for this week.
أنا في الخدمة لهذا الأسبوع.
You can talk to me.
يمكنك التحدث معي.
What's happening?
ماذا يحدث؟
What's the matter?
ما الأمر؟
Goodbye.
مع السلامة.
Who're you?
من أنت؟
Our school
مدرستنا
is close to outsiders.
قريب من الغرباء.
Do you want to see yourselves out
هل تريد أن ترى أنفسكم في الخارج
or let security staff
أو السماح لموظفي الأمن
see you out?
اراك بالخارج
Sorry, nice to meet you.
آسف ، سررت بلقائك.
I'm Ma Xiaoyi.
أنا ما شياويي.
The transfer student, right?
الطالب المنتقل ، صحيح؟
You're late.
انت متاخر.
That has cost you three morality points.
لقد كلفك ذلك ثلاث نقاط أخلاقية.
Alright, introduce yourself to your classmates.
حسنًا ، قدم نفسك لزملائك في الفصل.
Come forward.
تعال إلى الأمام.
Ma
أماه
Xiao-
شياو-
-cha
-تشا
Your name is Ma Xiaocha.
اسمك ما شياوتشا.
Can't you write your name?
لا تستطيع كتابة اسمك
You illiterate boy.
أنت فتى أمي.
[Ma Xiaoyi]
[ما شياويي]
Ma Xiaoyi.
ما شياويي.
"Yi" means an outstanding talent.
"يي" تعني موهبة بارزة.
That's why I got my name.
لهذا السبب حصلت على اسمي.
Nice to meet you, I'm Ma Xiaoyi.
سعدت بلقائك ، أنا ما شياويي.
This year,
هذا العام،
I hope I can graduate successfully,
أتمنى أن أتخرج بنجاح ،
so I want you...
لذلك أريدك ...
That's it.
هذا هو.
Take your seat. The empty one.
خذ مقعدك.  الفارغة.
All right.
حسنا.
Turn your book to page 26.
اقلب كتابك إلى الصفحة 26.
Tan Xin.
تان شين.
Where's your book?
أين كتابك؟
Sir. I forgot it at home.
سيد.  لقد نسيت ذلك في المنزل.
You...
أنت...
You're not serious enough about study.
أنت لست جادًا بما يكفي بشأن الدراسة.
Since you were punished to
منذ أن عوقبت ل
clean the classroom for a week,
تنظيف الفصول الدراسية لمدة أسبوع ،
you should change your attitude
يجب عليك تغيير موقفك
and thank teachers for their mercy
ونشكر المعلمين على رحمتهم
with your real action.
مع عملك الحقيقي.
Do you understand?
هل تفهم؟
Sit down.
اجلس.
Use the book with your deskmate.
استخدم الكتاب مع مكتبك.
Slowly.
ببطء.
Gently and carefully.
بلطف وحذر.
Jin Zhi.
جين تشي.
You beat me.
انت هزمتني.
Where did you get the glass?
من أين لك الزجاج؟
It's no bother.
لا يوجد عناء.
We're neighbors.
نحن جيران.
Never mind.
لا تهتم.
Be very careful.
كن حذرا جدا.
Be careful.
كن حذرا.
Jin Zhi.
جين تشي.
You're really capable.
أنت قادر حقًا.
Where did you get the glass?
من أين لك الزجاج؟
The shops are still closed.
المحلات لا تزال مغلقة.
I'm flattered.
أنا أشعر بالإطراء.
Anyone else
اي شخص اخر
can get the glass.
يمكن الحصول على الزجاج.
I broke the glass.
كسرت الزجاج.
It's inappropriate
انه غير مناسب
to let you buy it.
لتمكنك من شرائه.
We can't say that.
لا يمكننا قول ذلك.
I bought the fireworks.
اشتريت الألعاب النارية.
If someone must take the blame,
إذا كان يجب على شخص ما أن يتحمل اللوم ،
I should be to blame.
يجب أن ألوم.
There's no one to blame.
ليس هناك من يلوم.
It was just an accident.
كان مجرد حادث.
Yeah.
نعم.
In that case,
في هذه الحالة،
I'll set up the glass for you guys.
سأقوم بإعداد الزجاج لكم يا رفاق.
Guo Fucheng, what are you doing?
Guo Fucheng ، ماذا تفعل؟
I...I...
أنا ... أنا ...
I'm thinking.
انا افكر.
What are you thinking?
بماذا تفكر؟
Last week, I went...
ذهبت الأسبوع الماضي ...
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Stop!
قف!
What's under your sleeve?
ماذا تحت كمك؟
Take out.
أخرج.
Ms.
آنسة.
I won't do this again.
لن أفعل هذا مرة أخرى.
Please...give me one more chance.
من فضلك اعطينى فرصة اضافية.
Take it out.
أخرجه.
It's confiscated.
إنها مصادرة.
You're ridiculous.
كنت سخيف.
Ms.
آنسة.
You stand in the back.
أنت تقف في الخلف.
I want one student
اريد طالب واحد
to tell your answer.
لتقول إجابتك.
The new student.
الطالب الجديد.
Tell me your answer.
قل لي إجابتك.
I don't know.
لا أعلم.
Where are you going?
إلى أين تذهب؟
Answer the question!
اجب على السؤال!
I don't know.
لا أعلم.
You don't know!
أنت لا تعرف!
Behave yourself!
تتصرف بنفسك!
My class is not over.
صفي لم ينته بعد.
Stand up.
انهض.
Goodbye.
مع السلامة.
So unruly.
جامح جدا.
Can you just listen to me?
هل يمكنك فقط الاستماع إلي؟
We're listening.
تم الاستماع.
Do you know what he said?
هل تعرف ما قال؟
What?
لما؟
He was like this.
كان هكذا.
Ms, I don't understand your question,
السيدة ، أنا لا أفهم سؤالك ،
but I think I can't answer it.
لكني أعتقد أنني لا أستطيع الإجابة عليه.
So I'll stand in the back directly.
لذلك سأقف في الخلف مباشرة.
Then he went to the back right away.
ثم ذهب إلى الخلف على الفور.
He didn't say that much.
لم يقل ذلك كثيرا.
Then...
ثم...
I'm...
انا...
I'm a good actor.
انا ممثل جيد.
You know nothing of acting.
أنت لا تعرف شيئًا عن التمثيل.
The English teacher turned white with anger.
تحولت مدرس اللغة الإنجليزية إلى اللون الأبيض من الغضب.
That's the truth.
هذه هي الحقيقة.
This is our basketball court.
هذا هو ملعب كرة السلة لدينا.
This is our playground
هذا هو ملعبنا
where we have our PE class.
حيث لدينا فئة PE.
But we're seniors now,
لكننا كبار السن الآن ،
so we don't have PE classes often.
لذلك ليس لدينا فصول PE في كثير من الأحيان.
The library is ahead.
المكتبة في المقدمة.
You can study there.
يمكنك الدراسة هناك.
Forget it. I always feel sleepy when reading.
انسى ذلك.  أشعر دائمًا بالنعاس عند القراءة.
The same as me.
نفس الشيء مثلي.
If you have any questions,
إذا كان لديك أية أسئلة،
you can ask me.
يمكنك أن تطلب مني.
Is that Tan Xin?
هل هذا تان شين؟
Is that Ma?
هل هذا أماه؟
What are they doing there?
ماذا يفعلون هناك؟
I don't know.
لا أعلم.
Come up.
هيا تعال.
I have a question.
عندي سؤال.
Well,
نحن سوف،
What were you
ماذا كنت
disciplined for?
منضبط ل؟
Let bygone be bygone.
دع الماضي يكن ماضيا.
It's dishonorable.
إنه عار.
It's not good for you to know it.
ليس من الجيد أن تعرف ذلك.
We're the same kind of people.
نحن من نفس النوع من الناس.
Do you have
هل تملك
anything to ask me about?
أي شيء تسألني عنه؟
I'd better not. It's not good for me, either.
من الأفضل أن لا.  إنه ليس جيدًا بالنسبة لي أيضًا.
Am I that impressive?
هل أنا بهذا الإعجاب؟
What do they say about me?
ماذا يقولون عني؟
They say you were expelled
يقولون أنك طردت
by the previous school
من المدرسة السابقة
because you fought with others.
لأنك قاتلت مع آخرين.
I'm not a bully.
أنا لست متنمرًا.
I was upholding justice.
كنت أحافظ على العدالة.
I believe you.
واعتقد انكم.
You're a very chivalrous
أنت شهم جدا
guy in my eye.
الرجل في عيني.
What if
ماذا إذا
I'm not the kind of person you imagine.
أنا لست من النوع الذي تتخيله.
What kind?
اي نوع؟
The person who has a gang
الشخص الذي لديه عصابة
and can do anything he wants to do.
ويمكنه فعل أي شيء يريد القيام به.
Aren't you the kind of person?
ألست من هذا النوع من الأشخاص؟
Ma, you're what you are.
أماه ، أنت ما أنت عليه.
We're neighbors and classmates.
نحن جيران وزملاء.
Even if you're not an all-mighty person,
حتى لو لم تكن شخصًا قويًا ،
I'll protect you.
سأحميك.
Okay.
تمام.
You've become my best friend
لقد أصبحت صديقي المفضل
in the school.
في المدرسة.
If you need anything, just ask me.
إذا كنت بحاجة إلى أي شيء ، فقط اسألني.
Help each other.
ساعدوا بعضكم.
Right,
الصحيح،
I have two movie tickets for tonight.
لدي تذكرتي فيلم لهذه الليلة.
Do you want to go?
هل تريد الذهاب؟
I need to clean the classroom.
أنا بحاجة لتنظيف حجرة الدراسة.
I can't go.
لا استطيع الذهاب.
You go ahead.
تفضل.
But...
لكن...
Coming. Coming.
آت.  آت.
I smelt it from far away.
لقد صهرته من بعيد.
Grilled chicken.
دجاج مشوي.
Here. Give it to me.
هنا.  اعطني اياه.
The chicken is expensive.
الدجاج غالي الثمن.
Madam chicken brought it over herself.
سيدتي الدجاج أحضرته على نفسها.
Nonsense.
كلام فارغ.
Where's Mr. Tan?
أين السيد تان؟
He won't come back
لن يعود
until he messes something up.
حتى يعبث بشيء ما.
Forget him. Let's eat.
انساه.  لنأكل.
I'll go and get him.
سأذهب وأحضره.
No, no. Don't bother.
لا لا.  لا تهتم.
He's competitive since he was little.
إنه تنافسي منذ أن كان صغيراً.
He's also very stubborn.
إنه أيضًا عنيد جدًا.
Come. Come.
مثل.  مثل.
-Sit down.-Have a seat.
- اجلس. - اجلس.
You know, he'll come later
كما تعلم ، سيأتي لاحقًا
without our calling him.
دون أن ندعوه.
Just wait and see.
فقط انتظر وانظر.
Qiang has been like this,
كان Qiang هكذا ،
having a strong self-esteem.
امتلاك ثقة قوية بالنفس.
In their childhood, when they played in the yard,
في طفولتهم ، عندما كانوا يلعبون في الفناء ،
Qiang fell down suddenly
سقط تشيانغ فجأة
and began doing push-ups,
وبدأت في أداء تمارين الضغط ،
for fear that other kids would laugh at him.
خوفا من أن يسخر منه الأطفال الآخرون.
He did more than 200 push-ups.
قام بأكثر من 200 تمرين ضغط.
What happened next?
ماذا حدث بعد ذلك؟
He couldn't even pick up chopsticks.
لم يستطع حتى التقاط عيدان تناول الطعام He couldn't even pick up chopsticks.
Too many funny stories.
الكثير من القصص المضحكة.
♫She makes you so confused♫
♫ إنها تجعلك في حيرة من أمرك ♫
♫She is lonely in her heart♫
هي وحيدة في قلبها
♫Full of happy dreams♫
♫ مليئة بأحلام سعيدة ♫
Ma, how much did they cost?
أماه ، وكم كلفوا؟
You're my boss now.
أنت رئيسي الآن.
I want to eat drumsticks every day.
أريد أن آكل أفخاذ الطبل كل يوم.
All right.
حسنا.
Come on.
تعال.
Ma treats you to drumsticks.
ما يعاملك إلى أعواد الطبل.
Everyone of Class 8 has one.
كل شخص من الفئة 8 لديه واحد.
Eat, eat.
كلي كلي.
Here you are.
هنا أنت.
We want one.
نريد واحدة.
Okay. For the ones from Xiaoji Street.
تمام.  لأولئك من شارع Xiaoji.
Here you are.
هنا أنت.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
You're welcome.
على الرحب والسعة.
It's my pleasure. Just eat.
أنه من دواعي سروري.  كل فقط.
Ma, how much did they cost you?
أماه ، كم كلفتك؟
Don't save money for me.
لا تدخر المال من أجلي.
Money is the last thing I need.
المال هو آخر شيء أحتاجه.
Have you finished?
هل انتهيت؟
Guo Fucheng, have you finished?
قوه فوتشينج ، هل انتهيت؟
Ma bought us drumsticks.
ما اشترى لنا أفخاذ.
I need to finish it first.
أنا بحاجة لإنهائه أولا.
Well, let me introduce myself.
حسنًا ، دعني أقدم نفسي.
I'm Ma Xiaoyi, living on Xiaoji Street.
أنا Ma Xiaoyi ، أعيش في شارع Xiaoji.
Chen Cheng.
تشن تشنغ.
Wang Yong.
وانغ يونغ.
Gao Zhiyuan.
جاو تشي يوان.
We're not only classmates but neighbors.
نحن لسنا فقط زملاء الدراسة ولكن الجيران.
Let's play basketball together.
لنلعب كرة السلة معًا.
Sorry, I have an appointment.
آسف ، لدي موعد.
Maybe next time.
ربما في المرة القادمة.
Let's go.
لنذهب.
Wait for me. I'll go with you.
الانتظار لي.  سأذهب معك.
Why are you going?
لماذا انت ذاهب؟
I don't want to help her clean the classroom.
لا أريد مساعدتها في تنظيف الفصل.
Let's go. Let's go.
لنذهب.  لنذهب.
Come on.
تعال.
Miss Tan, hello.
آنسة تان ، مرحبا.
Do it.
افعلها.
-Okay. -Okay.
-تمام.  -تمام.
Hurry up.
عجلوا.
I can do this. Give it to me.
أستطيع أن أفعل ذلك.  اعطني اياه.
This is our work.
هذا عملنا.
But...
لكن...
What does this mean?
ماذا يعني هذا؟
They're all my friend.
كلهم صديقي.
Hurry up. Be quick.
عجلوا.  كن سريعا.
You can't do this for me.
لا يمكنك فعل هذا من أجلي.
Miss Tan. Leave this to us.
ملكة جمال تان.  اترك هذا لنا.
This is our duty.
هذا واجبنا.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
I can't bully you.
لا أستطيع أن أسلط عليك.
You're not,
أنت لست،
unless you don't let them do this.
ما لم تسمح لهم بذلك.
Be quick.
كن سريعا.
Since someone is cleaning the classroom,
بما أن شخصًا ما ينظف الفصل ،
you can go to the movie with me
يمكنك الذهاب الى الفيلم معي
But...
لكن...
That's it. Let's go.
هذا هو.  لنذهب.
I bought the tickets.
اشتريت التذاكر.
Hurry up, or we'll be late.
أسرع ، أو سوف نتأخر.
Go, go.
انطلق ، انطلق.
We can't just leave.
لا يمكننا المغادرة فقط.
It's okay.
حسنا.
Come on.
تعال.
Got it.
فهمتك.
Make sure it's very clean.
تأكد من أنها نظيفة جدًا.
It's done.
تم التنفيذ.
Hand me that one.
سلمني هذا.
Stop, stop. Be slow, be slow.
قف قف.  كن بطيئا ، كن بطيئا.
This.
هذه.
-Be careful. -Move aside.
-كن حذرا.  -تحرك جانبا.
Now you're proud.
أنت الآن فخور.
Good job.
أحسنت.
Come and push it.
تعال وادفعها.
I don't need to.
لست بحاجة لذلك.
I'm 100 percent believe
أنا أؤمن بنسبة 100٪
your skill.
مهارتك.
This is so great.
هذا شيء عظيم جدا.
It's a new window again.
إنها نافذة جديدة مرة أخرى.
Yes, yes.
نعم نعم.
It's a piece of cake.
انها قطعة من الكيك.
A piece of cake.
قطعة من الكعكة.
I'm so tired.
أنا متعب جدا.
Where's Tan Xin?
أين تان شين؟
I went to the movie with Ma.
ذهبت إلى الفيلم مع ما.
Why are you still here?
لماذا لا تزال هنا؟
Ma asked us to
طلب منا ما
do the cleaning for Miss Tan.
قم بتنظيف الآنسة تان.
Work hard.
اعمل بجد.
Okay.
تمام.
Let's go.
لنذهب.
Go.
اذهب.
Did you see how he walks?
هل رأيت كيف يمشي؟
He looks so cool.
إنه يبدو رائعًا جدًا.
I heard those from the next classroom
سمعت هؤلاء من الفصل التالي
are so rebellious
متمردة جدا
that no one dares to offend them.
لا يجرؤ أحد على الإساءة إليهم.
I can't believe Ma Xiaoyi
لا أصدق ما شياويي
asked them to do the cleaning.
طلب منهم القيام بالتنظيف.
Kids from Xiaoji Street
أطفال من شارع Xiaoji
are all simple and honest, such as us,
كلها بسيطة وصادقة ، مثلنا ،
good teenagers.
مراهقين جيدين.
I can't believe a greenwood hero
لا أصدق بطل غرينوود
came to the street.
جاء إلى الشارع.
I feel greatly proud.
أشعر بفخر كبير.
Greatly proud.
فخور جدا.
Stop, Guo Fucheng.
توقف ، قوه فوتشينج.
Your vocabulary
مفرداتك
has impressed me today.
لقد أعجبني اليوم.
You don't understand.
أنت لا تفهم.
It's difficult to meet a soulmate.
من الصعب مقابلة توأم الروح.
I have nothing to say to you.
ليس لدي ما اقوله لك.
Great.
عظيم.
Since Chen Chen has gone,
منذ رحيل تشين تشين ،
we have never seen
لم نر قط
such a fighter in Xiaoji Street.
مثل هذا المقاتل في شارع شياوجي.
I feel Ma Xiaoyi
أشعر ما شياويي
is quite strange.
غريب جدا.
He doesn't seem to be a hoody.
لا يبدو أنه هودي.
You know nothing.
انت لا تعرف شيئا.
In the movies, gang leaders
في السينما قادة العصابات
all have kind faces
جميعهم لديهم وجوه لطيفة
and say their prayers.
ويقولون صلاتهم.
People who look kind
الناس الذين يبدون طيبون
tend to be...
تميل إلى أن تكون...
Mom, I'm back.
أمي ، لقد عدت.
Dinner is ready.
العشاء جاهز.
Okay.
تمام.
Wenying.
وينينغ.
I remember there's
أتذكر أن هناك
a good old saying.
مقولة قديمة جيدة.
Afflictions are sometimes
الآلام في بعض الأحيان
blessings in disguise. Right?
بركات مقنعة.  حق؟
This is not a big deal.
هذه ليست صفقة كبيرة.
I'll set it up again.
سوف أقوم بإعداده مرة أخرى.
I've told you.
لقد قلت لك.
Aunt, I'm back.
عمة ، لقد عدت.
You...
أنت...
Lizi is back.
ليزي عادت.
You're back.
لقد عدت.
Lizi, I just made pancakes.
ليزي ، لقد صنعت الفطائر للتو.
Wash your hands and eat.
اغسل يديك وتناول الطعام.
Okay.
تمام.
Maybe she has
ربما لديها
made scorched pancakes again.
أعدت الفطائر المحروقة مرة أخرى.
Where's Tan Xin?
أين تان شين؟
Has she gone to the movie?
هل ذهبت إلى الفيلم؟
Didn't you go with her?
ألم تذهب معها؟
I'm not going.
أنا لن أذهب.
Aunt, you know,
عمة ، كما تعلم ،
the new student is a hoodie.
الطالب الجديد هوديي.
I heard
سمعت
he was expelled
تم طرده
from the previous school.
من المدرسة السابقة.
Nonsense.
كلام فارغ.
That's truth, aunt.
هذه حقيقة يا عمة.
I've seen him
لقد رأيته
act like a tyrant.
يتصرف مثل طاغية.
He even found someone to take his backpack,
حتى أنه وجد شخصًا يأخذ حقيبته ،
and asked juniors to
وطلبت من الصغار
help Tan Xin do the cleaning.
مساعدة تان شين في التنظيف.
Listen to me,
استمع لي،
maybe what Lizi said is true.
ربما ما قالته ليزي صحيح.
You Tan Xin should stay away from him.
أنت تان شين يجب أن تبتعد عنه.
I think he is a good boy.
أعتقد أنه ولد جيد.
You see, he called
كما ترى ، اتصل
to tell me
ليقول لي
he went out with Tan Xin.
خرج مع تان شين.
Tan Xin doesn't know these things.
لا يعرف تان شين هذه الأشياء.
What are you digging for?
ما الذي تبحث عنه؟
I forgot my homework at school.
لقد نسيت واجباتي المدرسية في المدرسة.
I have to go back, aunt.
يجب أن أعود يا عمة.
It's getting dark.
المكان يزداد ظلام.
You can let Tan Xin go with you
يمكنك أن تدع تان شين تذهب معك
when she comes back.
عندما تعود.
It's okay. I'll go myself.
حسنا.  سأذهب بنفسي.
Be careful on the road.
كن حذرا في الطريق.
Okay.
تمام.
Ride slowly.
اركب ببطء.
Bye, uncle.
وداعا عمي.
Worrisome kids.
أطفال مقلقون.
Wenying.
وينينغ.
Do we have larger plastic bags?
هل لدينا أكياس بلاستيكية أكبر؟
What a pretty girl.
يا لها من فتاة جميلة.
Hey, didn't you hear me?
مرحبًا ، ألم تسمعني؟
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
If you want to thank me,
إذا كنت تريد أن تشكرني ،
lend me 20 yuan.
اقرضني 20 يوان.
I want to buy some cigarettes.
أريد شراء بعض السجائر.
That's all I have.
هذا كل ما لدي.
Good. What a pretty and kind girl.
حسن.  يا لها من فتاة جميلة ولطيفة.
Stay away.
ابق بعيدا.
How dare you touch me?
كيف تجرؤ على لمسني؟
Listen,
استمع،
I don't get hit but do nothing.
لا أتعرض للضرب ولكن لا أفعل شيئًا.
Which school are you from?
من اي مدرسة انت
Here.
هنا.
Come on.
تعال.
Don't hide it. Take your hand away.
لا تخفيه.  خذ يدك بعيدا.
What are you looking at?
الى ماذا تنظرين؟
That's the uniform of Experimental Middle School.
هذا هو زي المدرسة الإعدادية التجريبية.
I've seen it.
لقد رأيت ذلك.
Since you know it,
بما أنك تعرف ذلك ،
you'd better not
من المستحسن ألا
show up around our school.
تظهر حول مدرستنا.
Who are you, talking to like this?
من أنت تتحدث إلى مثل هذا؟
I'm well-known here.
أنا معروف هنا.
Ma Xiaoyi of Class 8, Senior 3.
ما شياويي من الدرجة 8 ، كبير 3.
You just ask around.
أنت فقط تسأل من حولك.
Ma Xiaoyi.
ما شياويي.
Did you hear of it?
هل سمعت به؟
Zhiyuan.
زيوان.
Ms. Tan.
السيدة تان.
Why are you here?
لماذا أنت هنا؟
Are you going out at night?
هل ستخرج في الليل؟
She hasn't come back at this hour.
لم تعد في هذه الساعة.
I'm going to wait for her.
سأنتظرها.
Do you mean Tan Xin?
هل تقصد تان شين؟
Aunt.
عمة.
Ms. Tan.
السيدة تان.
I'm looking for you.
انا ابحث عنك.
You're home.
أنت في المنزل.
I'll go.
سأذهب.
Goodbye, Ms. Tan.
وداعا ، السيدة تان.
Come back. Come and eat pancakes.
عد.  تعال وتناول الفطائر.
I just cooked them.
لقد طهوتهم للتو.
My grandma is waiting for me.
جدتي تنتظرني.
Bye, Ms. Tan.
وداعا ، السيدة تان.
Come in, Zhiyuan.
تعال ، Zhiyuan.
Come and eat pancakes.
تعال وتناول الفطائر.
Okay.
تمام.
Are you here for Tan Xin?
هل أنت هنا من أجل تان شين؟
I...
أنا...
I came to you
جئت إليكم
to take comic books.
لأخذ الكتب المصورة.
Zhiyuan, eat pancakes.
Zhiyuan ، أكل الفطائر.
Okay.
تمام.
I just made them.
لقد صنعتهم للتو.
Ms. Tan, thank you.
السيدة تان ، شكرا لك.
Just eat.
كل فقط.
Lizi.
ليزي.
I haven't read these. You read them first.
أنا لم أقرأ هذه.  أنت تقرأهم أولا.
Not them.
ليس هم.
I want episode 6.
اريد الحلقة 6
Episode 6.
الحلقة 6.
It's kept by Tan Xin.
احتفظ بها تان شين.
You can ask her when she comes back.
يمكنك أن تسألها عندما تعود.
Ms. Tan.
السيدة تان.
It's late at night.
انها ساعة متأخرة من الليل.
Why hasn't Tan Xin come back?
لماذا لم يعد تان شين؟
She went to the movies with her classmate.
ذهبت إلى السينما مع زميلتها في الفصل.
She should be back soon.
يجب أن تعود قريبا.
You've read episode 6, haven't you?
لقد قرأت الحلقة 6 ، أليس كذلك؟
Why do you want it?
لماذا تريدها؟
I want to have a review.
اريد مراجعة.
Ms. Tan.
السيدة تان.
The pancake is nice.
الفطيرة جميلة.
I'll go back.
سأعود.
I'll take one.
سآخذ واحدة.
One more.
مرة اخرى.
You're welcome. It's enough.
على الرحب والسعة.  هذا يكفى.
Take one more.
خذ واحدة أخرى.
All right.
حسنا.
Thank you, Ms. Tan. I'll go back.
شكرا لك سيدة تان.  سأعود.
Goodbye, Ms. Tan.
وداعا ، السيدة تان.
Goodbye.
مع السلامة.
Look at him.
انظر اليه.
He read comic books more than once.
قرأ الكتب المصورة أكثر من مرة.
What a conscientious boy.
يا له من فتى ضميري.
Gao Zhiyuan.
جاو تشي يوان.
Did you come to me?
هل اتيت الي
No.
لا.
I went to your house to eat pancakes.
ذهبت إلى منزلك لأكل الفطائر.
Is it delicious?
هل هو لذيذ؟
Here you are.
هنا أنت.
I'll go home.
ساذهب الى البيت.
Slowly.
ببطء.
Gao Zhiyuan.
جاو تشي يوان.
I think there seems to be
أعتقد أن هناك ما يبدو
a little misunderstanding between us.
القليل من سوء الفهم بيننا.
Have a talk.
تحدث.
This afternoon, my friends said
بعد ظهر هذا اليوم ، قال أصدقائي
they liked my shoes and clothes,
لقد أحبوا حذائي وملابسي ،
so I gave them those
لذلك أعطيتهم هؤلاء
as they liked them so much.
لأنهم أحبوهم كثيرًا.
I didn't expect you to see that.
لم أكن أتوقع أن ترى ذلك.
Don't get me wrong.
لا تفهموني خطأ.
That's it.
هذا هو.
Don't go.
لا تذهب.
Why are you so rigid?
لماذا انت جامد جدا؟
What are you trying to say?
ماذا تحاول ان تقول؟
I mean,
أعني،
don't let it get out.
لا تدعها تخرج.
I'm not interested in your affairs.
أنا غير مهتم بشؤونك.
But I warn you.
لكني أحذرك.
Stay away from
ابتعد عن
Tan Xin and other neighbors.
تان شين وجيران آخرين.
Class 8, Senior 3, right?
الدرجة 8 ، كبير 3 ، أليس كذلك؟
Yes, yes.
نعم نعم.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Go.
اذهب.
Self-esteem
احترام الذات
is always accompanied by a sensitive and vulnerable heart,
دائمًا ما يكون مصحوبًا بقلب حساس وضعيف ،
and even lies.
وحتى الأكاذيب.
Sometimes
بعض الأحيان
we like to base our self-esteem
نود أن نبني احترامنا لذاتنا
on the approval of others,
بموافقة الآخرين ،
or even take others' opinions
أو حتى أخذ آراء الآخرين
as the whole support of our own life.
كدعم كامل لحياتنا.
Mom,
أم،
how long will we live here?
كم سنعيش هنا؟
Why do you ask about that?
لماذا تسأل عن ذلك؟
Your only work is to study hard.
عملك الوحيد هو الدراسة الجادة.
No. It decides
رقم تقرر
whether I should make friends with them.
ما إذا كان ينبغي علي تكوين صداقات معهم.
I don't want to live like before.
لا أريد أن أعيش كما كان من قبل.
Just as I made some friends,
مثلما كونت بعض الأصدقاء ،
we had to move.
كان علينا أن نتحرك.
But someone has seen us through.
لكن شخص ما رآنا من خلال.
Those who see through us
أولئك الذين يرون من خلالنا
but guard us
لكن حراسة لنا
are our treasures and more precious than our self-esteem.
هي كنوزنا وأغلى من تقديرنا لذاتنا.
The treasures
الكنوز
make our humble self-esteem
اجعل احترامنا لذاتنا المتواضع
glitter brightly.
بريق لامع.
Ma, you're back.
أماه ، لقد عدت.
Your lousy stupid idea.
فكرتك الرديئة الغبية.
Look at me.
انظر إليَّ.
I gave away my clothes and shoes.
تخلت عن ملابسي وحذائي.
I almost lost my pants.
كدت أفقد سروالي.
Have they been fooled?
هل تم خداعهم؟
Almost.
بالكاد.
Except Gao Zhiyuan.
باستثناء Gao Zhiyuan.
I should play my trump card.
يجب أن ألعب بطاقتي الرابحة.
What's this?
ما هذا؟
There are
هناك
all the birthdays of the kids' in Xiaoji Street in it.
كل أعياد ميلاد الأطفال في شارع Xiaoji فيه.
Where did you get it?
من اين حصلت عليه؟
I asked Tan Xin about it when watching the movie.
سألت تان شين عن ذلك عند مشاهدة الفيلم.
What's the use of this?
ما فائدة هذا؟
Useless.
بدون فائدة.
You don't understand.
أنت لا تفهم.
Based on my years of wandering life,
بناءً على سنوات حياتي الضالة ،
as long as people celebrate a birthday together,
طالما يحتفل الناس بعيد ميلادهم معًا ،
they'll be friends.
سيكونون أصدقاء.
Guo Fucheng's birthday is this weekend.
عيد ميلاد Guo Fucheng هو نهاية هذا الأسبوع.
[Tan Xin April 5, Lizi August, Guo Fucheng February 25, Gao Zhiyuan October 25, Chen Cheng April 5]
[تان شين 5 أبريل ، ليزي أغسطس ، قوه فوتشينج 25 فبراير ، قاو تشيوان 25 أكتوبر ، تشن تشينج 5 أبريل]
[beyond expression]
[ما بعد التعبير]
Follow me.
اتبعني.
Act as if we're strangers.
تصرف وكأننا غرباء.
Dr. Tan.
دكتور تان.
Okay, push it.
حسنًا ، ادفع.
It's good.
إنه جيد.
Good skills.
مهارات جيدة.
It's not because of my skills.
ليس بسبب مهاراتي.
The window was set up clumsily.
تم إنشاء النافذة بشكل أخرق.
The frame had been knocked askew.
كان الإطار مائلاً.
Drink some water. Thank you.
اشرب بعض الماء.  شكرًا لك.
You're welcome.
على الرحب والسعة.
I said he was so clumsy.
قلت أنه كان أخرق جدا.
I didn't want him to do this,
لم أكن أريده أن يفعل هذا ،
but he insisted.
لكنه أصر.
Not everyone can do this job.
لا يستطيع الجميع القيام بهذه المهمة.
Don't you have to hurry?
ألا يجب أن تسرع؟
Drink some water.
اشرب بعض الماء.
I have a lot of work to do.
لدي الكثير من العمل للقيام به.
Yes.
نعم.
Don't tell others you
لا تخبر الآخرين
worked for me.
عملت من أجلي.
Rest assured.
اطمئن، لا تشغل بالك.
Especially people on the street.
خصوصا الناس في الشارع.
Don't worry
لا تقلق
Workers like us always keep our mouths shut.
العمال أمثالنا يغلقون أفواهنا دائمًا.
See you. Good-bye.
أرك لاحقًا.  مع السلامة.
♫Give you all♫
♫ أعطيك كل شيء ♫
♫All my memory♫
♫ كل ذاكرتي ♫
♫I want to keep it breathing♫
♫ أريد أن أستمر في التنفس ♫
♫Give you all♫
♫ أعطيك كل شيء ♫
♫Nothing to do with my memory♫
♫ لا علاقة له بذاكرتي ♫
♫I want to leave it to cry in a dream♫
♫ اريد ان اتركها ابكي في المنام ♫
♫Time flies by♫
♫ الوقت يمر بسرعة ♫
♫Let bygones be bygones♫
وليكن ما مضى
♫Tightly hug the memory and kiss the memory♫
♫ عناق الذاكرة بإحكام وتقبيل الذكرى
♫To feel cherished♫
ليشعر بالاعتزاز
♫I'll be right there waiting for you♫
♫ سأكون هناك في انتظارك
♫I won't go anywhere♫
♫ لن أذهب إلى أي مكان ♫
♫I hum the melody softly♫
أنا أغمض اللحن بهدوء
♫Write to myself word by word♫
♫ أكتب لنفسي كلمة بكلمة
♫Give you all♫
♫ أعطيك كل شيء ♫
♫Love is a secret♫
الحب سر ♫
♫I want to keep it sweet in my heart♫
♫ أريد أن أبقيها حلوة في قلبي ♫
♫Give you all♫
♫ أعطيك كل شيء ♫
♫The problem of time♫
مشكلة الوقت
♫I want to make it absent in love♫
♫ أريد أن أجعلها غائبة في الحب ♫
♫Dreams are fragile and delicate♫
♫ الأحلام هشة وحساسة
♫Just let it break♫
♫ فقط دعها تنكسر ♫
♫It's always easier to do a thing than to know the reason♫
♫ من الأسهل دائمًا فعل شيء بدلاً من معرفة السبب
♫Not willing to give up♫
♫ لا ترغب في الاستسلام ♫
♫Years are messed up♫
♫ سنوات عابثة ♫
♫And full of imagination♫
♫ ومليء بالخيال ♫
♫Cherish every moment♫
♫ نعتز بكل لحظة
♫And things would be easier♫
♫ وستكون الأمور أسهل